那什么意思?
What's that mean?
塞医生
Dr. Sebastian.
两箱治肺结核的抗生素
Two pallets of antibiotics for tuberculosis.
可我们有相当于六箱用量的病人
We've got six pallets worth of patients.
斯塔克需要数学老师
Stoia Tucker needs a math lesson.
我明天带回来
I'm headed back tomorrow.
嘿
Hey!
嗨
把盒子搬走
Go get the boxes.
嘿，你
Hey there.
把那些盒子搬走，快，快
Move those boxes.Quick,quick
咱们搬，快，快
Let's move.Hurry,hurry,hurry
快，伙计，快
Let's go.Let's go,man. Hurry
我这有些非常特殊的药
I've got some very special medicine here.
是从宾州的荷西搞来的
It's from Hershey,Pennsylvania.
一人一支
One per person,one per person.
救命啊，塞阪大夫
Help,help,Dr. Sebastian
快来
Come quickly.
我儿子，他跌倒了，他摔在这里了
My son,he fell. He fell on this log.
我们在等他的药
We were just waiting for his meds.
左侧我听不到呼吸声了
I got no breath sounds on the left.
那个给我
Give me that.
对，他会没事的
Yeah,he's gonna be okay.
摔跤并没把肺摔出来
The fall didn't cause him to drop a lung
是肺的毛病导致了他跌倒，
The lung caused him to fall. TB chewed it up.
如果再活一年就够运气的了
He'll be lucky to live another year.
这是萨尼
This is Sarni.
我自己拿了支架的标签
I picked up the tab for the back brace myself.
可笑的是
The funny thing is,
支架比他们赖以活命的药
is that the brace cost more than the medicine
要贵不少
that would've prevented her from needing it.
那是你们的药
It's your medicine.
所有我们需要的抗生素
All of the antibiotics that we need
都在这里，你们的仓库
are right here in your warehouses
工厂里面
in your factories.
我们每年供应10,000支
We provide over 10,000 doses a year.
但……不够
Wh--which is not enough.
你知道我们想多贡献,但我们受制于人
You know we'd love to do more,,but our hands are tied.
新车，杰?
New car,Jerry?
我进来时看见了，漂亮
I saw it on the way in. Looks beautiful.
别私人化
Don't make this personal.
一路从德国运来的
All the way from Germany,too.
我知道会有很多红带子
I know that's a lot of red tape.
我不象你
I'm not like you.
我不以享乐为耻
I'm not ashamed of making a living.
我也知道你主修化学不只为赚钱
And I know you didn't become a ,chem major for the money.
那样就使我们目标一致了
Now,you want the same things that I want.
你只……
You just--
你得……
You have to--
你得再努力……
You just have to push a little--
你得再努力点
You have to push a little...bit harder.
再努力
Harder for it.
塞阪?
Sebastian?
打9-1-1
Call 9-1-1.
这没有医生吗?
Isn't someone here a doctor?
销售清单?
Selling subscriptions?
我听过20次了，你买了新自行车
I heard 20 and you get a new bike.
查塞阪博士在
Dr. Sebastian Charles collapsed
斯塔克演讲时晕倒
during a presentation at Stoia Tucker.
真的?
Really?
在他自我重压下倒塌了吗?
Crushed under the weight of his own ego?
哇
Wow.
你不敬佩任何人吗?
Is there nobody you admire?
在制造协会有个女孩
Well,there was this gal I met in Nam who could
能吹灭蜡烛，不用……
blow out a candle without using--
他认为是脑结核（TA）
He thinks it's TB.
他好在不是个梅毒专家
Good thing he's not the syphilis expert.
他需要验证意见
He wants a second opinion.
验证他自己，好啊
Second to his own. Okay.
不是TB
It's not TB.
是什么?
What is it?
哦 ，他要确切答案吗?
Oh,he wants specifics?
Lemma.
Lemma
尼克队的大球迷
Big Knicks fan
你过去从未有过这样的情形吗?
You've never had an episode like this before?
没有。他上月死了
No. He died last month.
愚蠢的跟他表兄分药吃
Stupidly tried to share his meds with his cousin
那药其实只够他一个人的
and they only had enough for one.
豪斯医生
Dr. House
我是查塞阪
I'm Sebastian Charles.
病人通常不是
Patients aren't usually
诊断程序的一部分
part of the diagnostic process
我是医生
Well,I'm a doctor.
听着，我知道你们挣钱不多
Listen,I know you guys don't make a lot of money--
我上个月给你们写了一张支票
I wrote your people a check last month.
哦，那就再写吧
Oh,well. Write us another one.
跟小蔡说，他有钱
Talk to Chase. He's rich
我爸爸，不是我
My dad,not me.
每分钟四个人死于TB
Every minute,four people die of TB.
哇
Wow!
你夜里如何安睡?
How can you sleep at night?
在非洲有人死于我们可以治……
There's people dying in Africa of a disease ,that we cured--
对，我知道
Yeah. I know
我看音乐会了
I saw the concert.
但是认真点，我们算算
But seriously,let's see.You sleep six hours
每晚你睡六个小时，那就是杀了...
That means every night you kill...
1,440 个人
1,440 people.
我猜你还是要睡觉的，但是拜托
I guess you gotta get some sleep,but come on
如果你再浪费个10分钟……
If you'd stayed up another ten minutes,
该可以救活40个人
you could've saved 40 lives.
今早你给家人们发消息了吗?
Do you send notes to the families in the morning?
那至少要花10分钟
That's gonna take at least ten minutes
那就是说又会有40个死，40个消息得发
So that's another 40 dead,another 40 notes.
干嘛你不回自己屋里用自疚拷打自己去呢?
Why don't you go rack yourself with ,guilt in your own room?
不，谢谢，我留下
No,thanks. I'll stay.
我想听听微分
I'd like to hear the differential.
卡梅伦医生
Dr. Cameron.
告诉这位医生为什么患者
Tell the doctor why it's not a good idea
不宜呆在这里
for the patient to be here.
他是免疫学家也是脑结核专家
He's an immunologist and a TB expert.
如果我们想听人说“这是TB”
That'll be very useful if we need somebody
会很有用
to say the words,"I think it's TB."
那是什么味?
What is that?
哦，那个……
Oh,that. I'm sorry.That's,uh--
是我的爽身粉
That's my body powder.
是我能找到唯一
It's the only thing I found
在撒哈拉有用的
that works in the Sahara
我习惯了
I'm kinda used to it
已经闻不到了
I don't even notice it.
还有人觉得象大象的粪味吗?
Who thinks it smells like an ,elephant dung smoothie?
我觉得还行
It smells okay to me.
那正是病人不能在这的原因
That is exactly why the patient ,shouldn't be in the room.
如果你没法告诉一个男人,他的古龙水让你想吐
If you can't tell a man that his cologne ,makes you want to puke,
你又怎么能告诉他他是白痴呢?
how are you gonna tell him that he's an idiot?
他不是白痴
He's not an idiot.
当然你那么说，他在屋里啊
Sure,you say that now. While he's in the room.
我功夫这样
I don't have time for this
-是 TB ,-不是
-It's TB ,-Nope
症状太杂
Symptoms are too varied.
如果你没见过10,000个病例
Well,if you haven't seen 10,000 cases,
我同意你的意见
I agree that's what you'd think.
我告诉你了他是白痴
I told you he's an idiot.
你说你要验证意见
You said you wanted a second opinion.
其实不要
No,actually.
我的赞助商们要
My backers wanted a second opinion.
对
Yeah
穿着有商标的鞋死掉
Doesn't look good if you drop dead
不好看啊
while wearing your shoe sponsor's logo.
是TB，而且我不会死
It's TB. And I'm not dying.
我需要你们给我植入PPD
I'm gonna want you to plant a PPD
引流痰液验证TB
and induce a sputum to confirm the TB
成像可确定进展
Imaging studies will determine the progress
然后，我想再给我肺
And,uh,I think we should probably
做个CT扫描吧
take a CT scan of my lungs,
那样有人就不会怀疑了吧?
just so that nobody second-guesses us?
不想那样
Wouldn't want that.
喂?
Hello?
不，我觉得好多了
No,I'm feeling much better
你做你能做的
Well,what you can do is, you can,uh,get your board
争取同意更多药品运输量……
to approve the increased med shipments,that--
抱歉，别试
Sorry.Uh-huh. Uh-huh. No,don't--don't try.
别尽力
Whatev--no,don't-- Don't do your best.
只做到，好吗?
Just get it done,okay?
是斯塔克
That's Stoia Tucker.
他们是好制药商
And they're the nice pharmaceutical company.
对不起，这违反医院规则
I'm sorry,but it's against hospital regs.
哦，我需要电话
Oh,I need the phone.
我们干嘛不集中对付你的健康问题呢?
Why don't we focus on getting you ,better right now?
那，你要干嘛，扔我出去吗?
Well,what do you do?Throw me out?
不，只是电话而已
No,just the phone
对不起，我们有急诊
Sorry,we've got an emergency.
赶紧走
Gotta go.
你房间里有电话
There's a phone in your room.
对，我猜也是
Yeah,I figured that there would be.
对，我想……
Right,I...I just thought--
这不象你在非洲惯呆的医院
It's not like the hospitals you may be ,used to in Africa.
我不知道是否便捷……
Um,I don't know what the facilities were like,so--
谢谢你
Thank you.
不要客气
You're welcome.
谢谢支票
And thanks for that check.
我得走了
I should go.
有面无名的可怜虫
The nameless poor have a face
华而不实的白人
and it's a pompous white man.
对啊，这混蛋
Yeah,what a jerk.
敢那样救人
Saving all those lives like that.
什么急事?
What's the emergency?
我忘了怎么遛狗了
I can't remember how to do walk-the-dog.
那家伙病了，快死了
The guy's sick.Maybe dying
我们还没做症状鉴别呢
We've forgotten all about doing ,a differential diagnosis.
你派我们去给他做……
You just sent us off to test him for--
嗯，我得把他轰出去啊
Well,I had to get him out of there.
现在我们可以坐一起骂他混蛋了
Now we can all sit around and call him an idiot.
谁先?
Who wants to go first?
他是对的
He's right
结核的症状很多
Tuberculosis could present hundreds ,of different ways.
用那个逻辑
Well,by that logic
医院里所有人都该治疗
everyone in the hospital should be treated.
并不是医院所有人在过去的20年里
Not everybody in the hospital's been exposed to it
都暴露在那样的环境中啊
for the last 20 years.
TB用数年致人死命
TB takes years to kill you.
两周前他还很健康
Two weeks ago,he was perfectly healthy.
现在却有多的可以写满白板的症状
Now he's got a whiteboard full of symptoms.
是不是代谢问题?
What about something metabolic?
欢迎登陆“马屁精号”
Welcome aboard the good ship Ass-Kisser.
航行的好天气啊
Nice day for a sail. Pucker up,me hardies.
不是代谢
It's not metabolic.
肾、肝、甲状腺都正常
Kidney,liver,and thyroid are all normal.
没糖尿病
No diabetes.
他的心脏呢?
What about his heart?
明显的，跟其他户外爱好者一样大
Obviously,big as all outdoors.
反常心律
Abnormal heart rhythm.
震动形式显示P-R的可变性
Wave forms show P-R variability.
很微小，但有
It's subtle,but it's there.
你觉得是心脏?心窦综合症？
You think it's his heart? Sick sinus syndrome?
没准
Loose throttle.
心跳时快时慢
Sometimes beats too fast,sometimes too slow.
导致昏倒
Causing him to pass out.
该可以导致这情形
It would account for the episode.
我要给他带遥感器
I'll put him on telemetry
做压力测试和超声波
do a stress test and an echocardiogram.
对待他同于其他住院病人一样
Treat him like every other hospital patient.
我要看到那个尽责的,满身擦粉的家伙穿上睡袍晃
I want to see that pious,body-powdered ,tush hanging out of his gown.
你能帮我弄这个吗?
Could you give me a hand with this thing?
我不记得要求做
I don't recall asking
压力试验和超声波
for a stress test or an echocardiogram.
那你要怎样，离开吗?
What are you gonna do,walk out?
社团赞助商不喜欢那样
Corporate sponsors aren't gonna like that.
伸胳膊
I need your forearm.
豪斯怎么想?
What's House thinkin'?
心窦综合症
Sick sinus syndrome.
那可比TB严重多了
Well,that's a lot more serious than TB.
那是PPD吗?
Is that a PPD?
如果48小时内变颜色……
If it changed color in the next 48 hours--
对，如果 House不认为是TB
Yeah,if,uh,if House doesn't think it's TB,
干嘛他不让你做呢?
why would he have you test for that?
只是要掩盖所有基本吧，我猜
Just...covering all his bases. I guess.
嗯
Uh-huh.
他不是那么干的人
He doesn't seem like a guy who--who does that.
我们安排你10:30 回声检查
We have you scheduled for a 10:30 echo.
干的好
Good for you.
我们一旦拒绝爱,
Every minute that we refuse to love one another,
就会有只小狗掉眼泪
another puppy cries another tear.
你生气是因为
You're just mad because he's closer
他比你接近诺贝尔奖
to a Nobel Prize than you are.
我还没钉上足够的瑞典人
And yet I've nailed more Swedish babes.
疯狂，疯狂的世界
Crazy,crazy world.
你知道那不止是去一趟斯德哥尔摩
It's not just a trip to Stockholm,you know.
是现金奖赏
It comes with a cash prize.
真的?
Seriously?
怪不得有那么多人追那个叫“和平”的玩意
No wonder everybody's going after ,that "peace" thing.
他每年救活千把人
He cures thousands of people every year.
你治愈多少,30?
You cure-- What,30?
麦当劳比你妈妈做更好吃的汉堡
McDonald's makes a better hamburger ,than your mother
因为他们做的多吗?
because they make more?
哦，我明白了
Oh! I see.
你恨他因为他救的生命
So you hate him because the lives he saves
不如你救的值钱？
aren't as good as the lives you save.
对，那是原因
Yeah. That's the reason.
诺贝尔发明了炸药，我不要他粘血的钱
Nobel invented dynamite. I won't accept ,his blood money.
我的头顶要我的命
The top of my head's killing me.
嗯
Mm.
我们在解剖学时花一周时间对付“头顶”
We spent a week doing "top of head" in anatomy.
我知道那个位置
I know just where it is.
哇
Ow!
那不是我的头顶
That is not the top of my head.
对临床来说够近了
Ah,close enough for a clinic.
你的窦阻塞了
Your sinuses are clogged.
根据你手臂的划痕来看,
Judging by the scratches on your hands,
我猜是只新猫
I'm guessing a new cat.
是我妈妈的，她死了
It was my mother's. She's dead.
你养死猫?
You keep a dead cat?
不，我妈妈死了
No. My mother's dead.
哦，可怜的猫
Oh. Poor cat.
你过敏了
You're allergic
我们可以用抗组胺药控制
We can control it with antihistamine
一天一片
One pill a day.
药片?
Pills?
你不喜欢吞咽
You don't like to swallow.
不奇怪
Not surprised.
不要药片了
Forget the pills.
我给你开个鼻腔喷雾器
I'm gonna give you a nasal spray.
类固醇?
Steroids?
还有别的能给我吗?
Is there something else you can give me?
如果你住在河边,
Well,if you lived by the river,
我有袋子
I've got a bag.
嘿，压力试验正常
Hey. Stress test was normal.
但EKG不正常
But his EKG was not normal.
回声检查正常
Echo's normal.
给你两分，给我一分
Two for you,one for me.
我们得找个解扣的
We need a tiebreaker.
回声和压力很可信
Echo and stress test are way more reliable.
倾斜试验
Tilt table test.
从来就无效
That never works.
跟你打赌一周的门诊工作时间，有效
Bet you a week's clinic duty it does.
好
You're on
喜欢这家伙吗?
Like this guy?
你老说我们的观点与病人无关
You always tell us our opinion of ,the patient's irrelevant
医学上，无关
Medically,it's irrelevant.
但却与你有关
It says something about you.
你认为
You figure anybody
任何关心非洲人生死的人
who gives a crap about people in Africa
就有关了吗?
must be full of it?
对
Yes.
我们关心自己的亲友
There's an evolutionary imperative ,why we give a crap about
有进化理论作为理由
our family and friends
同样有进化理由支持我们
And there's an evolutionary imperative
对其他人漠不关心
why we don't give a crap about anybody else.
如果我们无任爱人
If we loved all people indiscriminately
我们就失去功效了
we couldn't function,Mm
所以伟大的人道主义者跟我们一样自私?
So the great humanitarian's as selfish ,as the rest of us?
只是不象表现的那么热衷
Just not as honest about it.
你也老说动机不相干
Well,you also always tell us motives ,are irrelevant.
查医生,你的心脏对付
Dr. Charles,your heart's handling the changes
倾斜功能发挥正常
in orientation just fine.
EKG上没有停顿
No pauses on your EKG.
而豪斯就要对他的赌注...
And House drives in for the lay-up and...
不，反对！
No! Rejected!
这个按钮是干什么的?
What does this knobby thing do?
我在可受范围之内
I'm within protocol range,you're not gonna get
你得不出不同答案
a different result.
我想的是,
The way I figure it is,
如果这个东西在6就能显示问题...
if this could show you problems at six...
想像一下如果到10会发生什么？
imagine what it'll tell you if you ,crank it to ten.
豪斯? 是你吗?
House? Is that you?
能到11吗?
Does it go to 11?
停止好吗？
Would you stop?You lost
我被安排周四和周五出诊
I'm scheduled for clinic duty Thursday and Friday.
好了，我开始觉得恶心了
All right,I'm beginning to feel nauseous.
你别弄了会坏的
Would you turn the damn thing off ,before you break it?
好吧，我开始头晕了
Okay,I'm getting dizzy
我看不见了，而且快晕过去了
I can't see,and I'm gonna pass out.
我赢了
I win.
那样的速度连宇航员也会晕
Those speeds,astronauts throw up.
我说的不是恶心
I'm not talking about the nausea.
是相关试验结果
The test revealed the problem
是吗? 豪斯疯了?
Yeah? House is insane?
他刚做的是……
What he just did--
滥用和非专业的，但是...
Abusive and unprofessional.But...
如果没那么做，我们就不会发现问题
if hadn't have done it,we wouldn't,have seen the problem.
你有一个反常的P-R间歇
You've got an abnormal P-R interval.
可能很危险
Could be dangerous.
可能致命,尤其是在非洲
Possibly fatal,particularly if you're in Africa,
远离先进的医疗系统
away from advanced medicine.
我需要起搏器吗?
I'm gonna need a pacemaker?
我们安排你今天下午做手术了
We've scheduled you for surgery this afternoon.
我们可以在任意地点维持你的起搏器
We'll be able to maintain your ,pacemaker from anywhere
你只需要一段时间找个电话线
you just need to get yourself to a ,phone line every few months
或者你可以加入我们的门诊
Or better yet,you could join me at ,one of my clinics.
我被宠坏了
I'm kinda spoiled.
我们可以给你一个带风景的小屋,你喜欢沙子吗?
Well,we'll get you a hut with a view,,do you like sand?
我的意思是药物，没有PET扫描
I meant medically. No PET scans.
没有核磁共振，简直荒谬
No MRIs-- This is ridiculous.
查医生……我知道,医院规章
Dr. Charles-- I know,I know. Hospital regulations.
亲爱的，请坐
Darling,have a seat.
快走
Come on.
你聪明，会适应
You're smart. You'll adapt.
我们上还是下?
We going up or down?
地下室，好吧
Basement. All right.
你或许会发现……
You might even find that,uh,
没有技术的支撑
without the technological crutches,
你变成了更棒的诊断专家
you become a better diagnostician.
我的心脏能应付这个，对吧?
My heart can handle this,right?
到目前为止，是嘉年华让你出问题的
Uh,so far,just carnival rides have set you off.
当你见到那些人，他们让你改变
When you meet these people,it changes you.
我们该在晚餐后谈论这些
We should talk about it over dinner.
你是邀我去非洲还是约会?
Are you asking me to Africa or on a date?
哦，我可以邀你走半个地球
Oh,I can ask you halfway around the world,
却不能邀你去一条街远的餐厅吗?
I can't ask you to a restaurant a block away?
一个是工作，令一个是……
Well,one's a job and the other's-- Uh-huh
对，医院规章，不能约会病人，对吧?
Yeah, Hospital regs. You can't date ,patients,right?
我不打算...
I wouldn't want to...
拿你宝贵的客观性冒险
risk your precious objectivity.
顺便说，你哪个问题也没回答呢
You haven't answered either question, by the way
你不觉得客观性重要吗?
You don't think objectivity's important?
我觉得象House那样依赖客观的医生
I think doctors like House cling to objectivity
很象依赖毯子的三岁小孩
like a three-year-old to a blanket.
别激动，保持冷静
Don't get too worked up. Stay calm.
保持正确的看法
Stay cool and maintain the correct perspective.
他们正常的唯一裂痕是
The only flaw in their argument
当百万人濒死时
is that when you have millions of people dying,
正确的看法是由
the correct perspective is to be yelling
你的肺顶部呼喊出来的
at the top of your lungs.
对不起，我的头要了我的命……
I'm sorry,my head is--is killing me--
坐在台阶上
Sit on the step.
那你到底跟不跟我出去呢?
So you gonna go out with me or not?
你的心跳正常
Your heart rate's normal.
当然，只是一阶台阶而已
Yeah,of course it is. It's one flight of stairs.
我会没事的
I'm gonna be fine.
我的手真小……
My hand's a little--
你错了
You were wrong.
嗨，我有感觉，我尽力了
Hey. I have feelings. I'm trying my best.
对你不够吗?
Isn't that enough for you?
反常的EKG是真的吗?
The abnormal EKG was real?
不是心窦综合症
It's not sick sinus syndrome.
感谢上帝我们在放起搏器之前发现了
Thank God we found out before we ,put the pacemaker in
感谢上帝你把他领近了楼梯间
Thank God you dragged him into a stairwell
好让他的心跳加速
to get his heart racing.
我们走楼梯，楼梯在楼梯间
We were taking the stairs. They keep them ,in the stairwell.
这家伙是个自私的混蛋，他干嘛不……
The guy's a selfish jerk. Why would he--
你干嘛说他自私?
Why would you say he's selfish?
因为他跟福满谈了
Because he's been talking to Foreman.
我没有，我只是发表意见
No,I haven't.I'm just giving my opinion
这种利他主义不自然……
This kind of altruism doesn't just naturally--
完美的简述，但他还是病人
Excellent briefing. Hey,the guy's still sick.
我们可以谈一下吗?
Can we talk about that?
头疼指向神经系统问题
Headaches point to a neurological problem
声学神经瘤
Acoustic neuroma.
脑瘤导致头晕眼花
Brain tumor causes dizziness,
意识丧失
loss of consciousness.
与呼吸和心跳节律不稳混合
Mess with,uh,breathing patterns,heart rhythms--
做核磁共振
Get an MRI.
喂?
Hello?
哦，对不起，我马上下来
Oh,I'm sorry. I'll be right down.
没问题
No problem
我会补偿性多做一个小时
I'll do an extra hour to make up
我出诊时间晚了
I'm late for my clinic duty.
这里，去装我几个小时
Here,go be me for a couple of hours
突发腹泻，发烧
Explosive diarrhea,fever.
可能是流感
It's probably the flu.
哇
Wow
你真棒，是哈佛的吧?
You're good. You a Harvard boy?
你不是奥西
You're not Hill,Oliver.
不，是卡希
No. Carter,Cecelia.
他们把你安排错了房间，希
They put you in the wrong room,Cecelia.
卡太太
Mrs. Carter.
抱歉
Sorry.
我一会儿就来
Uh,I'll just be a few more minutes.
没法按顺序，全都乱套了
Don't take these in order,everything falls apart.
我得癌了
I have cancer.
我可以感觉到肿块
I felt a lump.
-我找个护士,-行
-I'll go get a nurse.,-Yeah
过一、两个小时再见
See you in an hour or two.
躺平
Lie flat
举起你左臂到头下面
Lift your left arm up and under your head.
这吗? 行
Right there? Yeah.
我今早感觉到的
I felt it this morning.
我表姐也有
Oh,my cousin had the same thing.
没事
It's nothing.
我们下个周期再检查
We should check it again on your next cycle
但你真没什么可担心的
but you really don't have anything to worry about
他们也是这么告诉当娜的,她六个月就死了
That's what they told Donna. ,She was dead in six months.
听我说，边缘很滑，能移动
Listen,the edges are smooth,it has mobility.
是良性的征兆
It has all the earmarks of a benign--
我干嘛要信你?
Why should I believe you?
因为你想催我走?
Because you're trying to rush me out of here?
活体检查的假阳性……
The risks of a false positive on ,a biopsy outweigh--
要么你安排活体检查,要么我跟你上级说话
Either you do the biopsy,,or I talk to your superior.
选哪个...
Which is it...
豪斯医生?
Dr. House?
我来安排活体检查
I'll arrange the biopsy.
谢谢
Thanks.
他约我出去
He asked me out
我很震惊
I'm shocked.
我在病人不约你时才震惊
I'm--I'm shocked when patients don't  ask you out
他还约我去非洲
He also asked me to come to Africa.
天啊，他动作挺快啊
Boy,he moves fast.
我看这两个问题有两个对象
I think the two questions had ,two different objectives.
你喜欢他?
You like him?
英俊的单身男士，天才医生
Good-looking single guy,genius doctor.
关怀全世界
Cares about the world.
我看你的答案是不
I take it you said no.
你觉得我那么在意规矩……
You think I'm that hung up on rules--
他不是豪斯
He's not House.
那什么都没有
There's nothing there.
对，有
Yeah,there is.
我让你植入PPD了吗?
Did I ask you to plant a PPD?
是阳性的
It was positive.
他得TB了
He's got TB.
他当然有TB
Well,of course he's got TB!
这家伙在丛林里20年了
The guy's been in the jungle for 20 years!
如果他红眼病测试阳性
If he tested positive for pinkeye,
你觉得那是他的大问题吗?
would you think that was his big problem?
我做了一个试验，是阳性的,那有问题吗?
I did a test,it was positive. ,Why is that  a problem?
因为现在他在他的胳膊上,有了一个红色的大靶子
Because now he's got the ,big red target on his arm,
那个顽固的混蛋会以为他对了
the stubborn jerk thinks he's right.
他就不会让我们做其他试验了
He won't let us do any more tests.
也许他不是唯一一个顽固的混蛋
Maybe he's not the only stubborn jerk!
我也做了LP ，低糖
I did an LP too. Low glucose.
他的瑟丹比率增高了
And he has an increased sed rate.
所有结果指向结核
Everything screams tuberculosis.
不是所有
Not everything!
如果任何症状都由TB导致
If any of the symptoms are caused by the TB
那该偏离我们的诊断
it would throw off our diagnosis.
你是对的
You're right.
我们得治疗TB
We gotta treat the TB.
谁知道呢？也许，他就……好起来呢
Who knows? Maybe he'll just...get better.
你会喜欢那么，是吧?
You'd like that,wouldn't you?
所以，是TB 也不是TB?
So it's TB but not TB?
我复杂
I'm complicated.
那家伙知道肺结核
The guy does know tuberculosis.
-如果他说可以证明,-那家伙甚至不是个真正的医生
-If he says it can manifest ,-Guy's not even a real doctor.
他是活人连续剧
He's a human telethon.
那是你跟他的问题吗?
Is that your problem with him?
你每天都见伪君子，,这个怎么这么特殊?
You see hypocrites everyday. ,Why is this guy so special?
你以为我会用伪善的,态度对待伪善吗?
You think I have a hypocritical ,attitude to hypocrisy?
问题是，字母表有26个字母
The problem is,there are 26 ,letters in the alphabet,
他只用两个
and he only uses two of them.
他用一个诊断对待千百个病人
He treats thousands of patients ,with one diagnosis.
他知道结果，是骗人
He knows the answer going in. It's cheating.
所以是因为他是那些没用专家的一名?
So it's all because he's one of them ,useless specialists?
哦，我是不是伤了大肿瘤专家的感情了?
Oh,did I hurt the big-time oncologist's ,itty-bitty feelings?
你对有癌的人是个很大的帮助
You're a big help to patients who ,actually have cancer.
其他时候很烦人
Other times,you're just annoying.
你完蛋了
You've outdone yourself.
我也是那么说的
I'll say.
我的萨拉掩护了一块T骨牛排
My salad's covering a free T-bone steak.
卡希，记得吗?
Cecelia Carter,remember her?
上周他们说“神秘炖菜”，他们欠我的
Last week they said it was "mystery stew," ,they owe me.
她在我办公室哭呢
She was just in my office crying
因为你对她误诊
because of the way you treated her.
那不象你
That doesn't sound like you.
所以很可能根本不是
Then it probably wasn't.
我知道你很喜欢吓唬人
I get that you like to shock people.
因为愚蠢而以吓唬人为满足
Stun them out of complacency,out of stupidity.
但这个女人以为自己有癌了
But this woman thought she had cancer.
她胸部有个肿块
She had a lump in her breast.
你到底达到什么目的?
What were you trying to accomplish?
我来问你
Let me ask you something.
如果这是其他的医生,
If this were another doctor,
我们说，她抱怨的是……
if the patient were complaining about,let's say,
我不知道，福满，你就变成了
I don't know,Foreman,you'd just dismiss this
一个妄想的婊子听另一个妄想婊子的胡话
as the paranoid bitching of ,another paranoid bitch.
那么病例归档就该放在“妄”下面
And file it under "P" for--
妄想?
Paranoid?
我不是
Am not.
-你对,-好
-You're right,-Good
今天完事前
Apologize to her
向她道歉
before the end of business today.
你对希干什么了?
What did you do to Ceci?
不知道
I have no idea.
只有萨拉，早餐吃多了
Just the salad today. Big breakfast.
嘿
Hey.
Levofloxacin?
你对TB有抗性.
You have a resistant strain of TB.
哇，你就拿着这些来了
Wow,you just walk right in with these.
那是我们当医生干的活
That's what we doctors do.
我们写下药名,
We write down the name of some medicine,
然后有人给我们
and someone gives it to us.
你知道，世界上有的地方
You know,there's parts of the world ,where you get knifed
带这个要带上刀子
walking around with this.
我的意思是，正规的东西就够糟了...
I mean,the regular stuff's bad enough,but...
治疗抗性?
...treatment for the resistant strain?
他们花六块钱买这个
They get $6.00 a tablet for that.
而我得吃两年
And I'll take it for two years.
链霉素
Streptomycin.
那是两个单位
Now,that's two grand
10个单位就能救活一个人
Ten grand,cure one person.
我有过一个病人，加尼
I had a patient in,uh,Jani once.
是个有……
It was a mother had--
三个孩子的母亲
had,uh,three little boys.
她得了TB
She had resistant TB.
她买不起这些
She couldn't afford these.
她连生计都困难
She couldn't afford bread.
我们给她常规药……
We gave her the regular stuff,but,uh--
不出所料，她死了
No surprise,she died.
我很难过
I'm sorry.
我不吃这些药
I'm not taking these pills.
因为她吃不起,
Because she couldn't get them,
你就不吃吗?
you're not gonna take them?
太愚蠢了
That's insane.
为什么? 因为我比她好?
Why? 'Cause I'm better than her?
因为任其死亡不好,
Because letting her die was wrong,
任你死亡也是不对的
but letting you die is just as wrong.
也许我不会死
Well,maybe I won't die.
也许那样就会有人信我的故事了
Maybe somebody will pay more attention to my story
他认为抗生素公司需要
He figured the Fromsudecal companies ,need something big
更大的力量推动他们行动
to force them into action
这样媒体报道比非洲村民之死更多
This is gonna get a lot more media play than ,a thousand African villagers dying
所以他不吃药
So he won't take the pills.
《新闻周刊》找你
Newsweek's calling you.
他也不再同意做任何检查了
And he won't agree to any more tests.
他有他的诊断
He has his diagnosis.
看到你不听我的发生什么了吧?
See what happens when you don't listen to me?
也许百万生灵由此得救
Maybe millions of lives get saved.
对，那正是我的观点
Yeah. That's my point.
心律加快，夜间盗汗
Increased heart rate. Night sweats.
意识丧失
Loss of consciousness.
还有粗鲁的性行为
Besides rough sex,
他们的共同点是什么?
what do they all have in common?
T……不是TB
T--It's not TB!
他的植物神经系统?
His autonomic nervous system?
我们知道不是脑瘤
We know that it's not a brain tumor.
还有什么能吞噬他的神经?
So what else could be eating his nerves?
自律神经系统？导致羞愧感知失灵？
Fabry's? Autonomic dysregulation syndrome ,Shy-drager Syndrome
没关系
It doesn't matter
他不会让我们检查他
He won't let us test him.
按照我的意思，查塞阪博士是个白痴
In my opinion,Dr. Sebastian Charles is an idiot.
对，你可以引证我的话
Yeah,you can quote me
C-U-D-D-Y.
塞阪拒绝挽救生命的计划
Sebastian is refusing life-saving treatment.
他拒绝TB的治疗
He's refusing TB treatment.
你不觉得他有TB
You don't think he has TB
因此，你少担心点吧
Ergo,you should care less.
他不让我检查他
He won't let me test him.
那你想让我干什么?
And what do you want me to do about it?
按倒他
Hold him down.
你跟卡希道歉了吗?
Have you apologized to Cecelia Carter yet?
相信我，她不想听我说话
Trust me,she doesn't want to hear from me.
你看，那家伙在自杀
Look,the guy is killing himself
我是唯一认为这是坏事的人吗?
Am I the only one who realizes ,this is a bad thing?
如果他是基督教科学家
If he was a Christian Scientist
拒绝药物，我们有18位律师……
refusing meds,we'd have 18 attorneys--
你在化妆
You're putting on makeup.
那可不是我的好消息，是吧?
That's not a good sign for my side,is it?
塞阪在三点要召开记者会
Sebastian has called a press conference for 3:00.
他让我到场
He's asked me to be there
让我确认诊断和预后
to confirm the diagnosis and the prognosis.
你跟他一样是媒体婊子
You are as big a media whore as he is.
我当然是
Of course I am
不是我同意他的做法
It couldn't possibly be that I think he's right.
只是想做他那样做的一部分而已
That I'd like to be a small part of ,what he's doing.
哦，婊子可以喜欢做爱,那并不表示她们就不是婊子
Oh,whores can like the sex. ,Doesn't mean they're not whores.
再涂上那样的眼影……
And with that eye shadow--
我彻底完蛋了，对吧?
I am totally screwed,aren't I?
彻底
Totally.
你觉得怎样?
How you feelin'?
有点虚弱
A little weak.
你今天就算不错了
You're having a good day.
症状会越来越接近你的肺部
The symptoms will quickly focus more,and more on your lungs.
你会发现讲话困难
You'll find it difficult to talk,
最终无法呼吸
and eventually breathe at all--
我认为我知道最终的结果
I think I know what I'll have to look forward to.
我知道
I know
我只是来问
I just came to ask
你是否愿意接受任何治疗
if you'd be willing to accept any treatment.
不，如果你想吓唬我……
No,if you're trying to scare me into--
不是
No.
减轻的治疗
Palliative treatment.
麻醉药
Narcotics.
芬太努片,吗啡输液,任何
Fentanyl Patch,morphine drip,whatever it takes.
我们可以尽力使你的临终之时舒服些
We can make your last days fairly comfortable.
如果你还有这么好的一天,
And if you have another good day,
或许吃晚餐吧
maybe dinner.
谢谢
Thank you.
你想要第三世界的治疗吗？给你
You want third world treatment? You got it.
天啊，这挺热吧
Boy,is it hot here in Jani.
你干嘛?
What are you doing?
我干嘛?
What am I doing?
在小屋里把所有的东西都放地板上
Putting everything on the floor at the hut.
嗯
Uh-oh.
有移动照片的魔术盒是什么?
What's the magic box with the moving pictures?
你觉得他是伪君子吗?
You think he's a hypocrite?
伪君子？不
Hypocrite? No.
非洲人都有移动电话和活水
Everybody in Africa's got cell phones ,and running water
哈
Ha.
这东西冲不下去
This thing just will not flush.
你真的以为你到这来
Do you really think that if you come in here
把温度搞热点
and make it a little hot,
有味儿点，我就投降
make it smell a little,that I'm just gonna fold
并放弃所有对我有意义的事情吗？
and abandon everything that matters to me?
那边还有糟糕的卫生设备
Lousy sanitation over there too.
你跟他们不同
You are not the same as them.
你的生命不同
Your life is not the same
结果你用假装是他们,而使他们的真正经历大打折扣
And you're cheapening everything they're ,going through by pretending you are
我是一样的，我不特别
I am the same. I'm not special.
你不能要求象第三世界的,病人那样被治疗
You can't demand to be treated like any ,third world sick person
然后召开记者会
and call a press conference!
他们特殊地对待我
They treat me special.
那不代表我就特殊
That doesn't mean I am.
哪有不占这样便宜的
And what kind of selfish jerk
自私的白痴呢?
wouldn't take advantage of that fact?
都是可以预防的
It's all preventable.
斯塔克就在这里制药
Stoia Tucker makes medications right here
就在新泽西，他们的仓库里满是药品
in New Jersey,they have warehouses ,full of the stuff
远超过需要的储量
There's more than enough to go around.
那么如果我可以得到,
So if I can get 'em,
雷玛为什么不能呢？
why can't Lemma?
奎莫呢?
Why can't Quesmo?
萨尼呢?
Why can't Sarni?
又有人刚刚死去
Another person just died.
你们的愤怒在哪里?
Where is your outrage?
不，我并不打算牺牲自己
No,I have no intention of martyring myself
我只是把我自己...
I'm just putting myself...
当然，他们快死了
Sure,they're dying.
但被很很地敲了一下
But it's got a great beat.
在那样的灯光下一定热死了
Must be hot as hell under those lights.
对
Yep.
嘿，干嘛呼我？他没事吗？
Hey,why the page? He okay?
他昏迷
He's in a coma.
我需要你给希……道歉
I need you to apologize to Ceci...cecily
卡太太？为什么？
Mrs. Carter? For what?
随便因为什么
For whatever I did.
你什么也没做啊
You didn't do anything.
那一直就是我的立场
That has been my position all along.
他的胸部X光片呈阴性
His chest X-Rays are negative
所以他此刻不传染
So he's not contagious at this point
他目前的情况稳定
His condition's currently stable.
你是否注意到……
Do you ever notice
历史上自我牺牲的女人……
how all the self-sacrificing women in history--
圣女贞德，特赖莎修女……
Joan of Arc,Mother Theresa--
再想不出来了……
Can't think of any others--
他们都是孤独而死
They all die alone
而男人，却是乱七八糟的，疯狂
The men,on the other hand,get so much fuzz,,it's crazy.
这世界不公啊
It's an unfair world.
豪斯，她当时害怕而且不讲理
House,she was scared and unreasonable
用肺癌侮辱一个女人
Insulting a woman with breast cancer.
那样态度不够正面
That's a move best left to the pros.
坦白的讲，你不够专业
Frankly,you don't have the chops.
我没侮辱她
I didn't insult her!
我只是按她的要求,做了个不必要的活体检查
I did the unnecessary biopsy,like she wanted
是阴性的，跟我早料到的一样
It was negative,like I knew it would be
要是你怎么办？管他们叫专家吗？
What'd you do? Call 'em perky?
你早过了那样发神经行医的年头了
You are years away from mad skills like that.
我需要你道歉
I need you to apologize.
卡迪那样做因为她以为是你
Cuddy's only doing this because ,she thinks it's you.
欢迎到地球
Welcome to the world.
人跟人不同，也会被区别对待
Everyone's different,and everyone ,gets treated different.
你跟那个抗争，会被卷起来死于TB
You try fighting that,you wind up dying of TB.
你干嘛呢?
What are you doing?
检查病人的自律神经系统
Testing the patient's autonomic nervous system.
当然
Of course.
他的内部加热和通风系统关了
His internal heating and ventilation ,should be off.
他该不会出汗
He shouldn't be able to sweat
那就是他用那么可怕的爽身粉的原因
That's why he's got that awful body powder
拿走它，打开暖气，把他安置在灯光下
Take it away,crank up the heat,stick him ,under the lights.
他无法冷却自己
He can't cool himself.
他该变得鲜红
He should be turning bright red
图像还可以啊
Picture's fine.
我请求斯塔克拯救这些生灵
I'm asking Stoia Tucker to save these lives,
数百万生灵，包括我
millions of lives,including my own.
豪斯医生
Dr. House.
我谢谢你如果你能让我们……
I would appreciate it if you left us all--
把那个拿开
Get that outta my face.
你想证明什么，豪斯?
What are you trying to prove,House?
豪斯医生，如果你能离开我会感谢你的
Dr. House, I would appreciate it ,if you left the room
他象只猪一样出汗
He's sweating like a pig.
这有上百度
It's a hundred degrees in here,House,
－－是你关的暖气,－－他们能听见我吗?
because you turned up the thermostat,-- Did they hear me?
媒体，他们听呢吗?
The media,did they listen?
他已丧失意识
He's disoriented.Where's the--
他们得听我说
They have to hear me.
他的动脉压力增高了
His arteries are clamping down.
所有人离开房间
I want everybody out of her now!
把压力车推来，他需要做胃部引流
Get the crash cart. He's having a cardiac arrest.
让他们出去
Get them out!
所有人，出去
Everyone--I want everyone out of here now
清理
Clear.
加油啊，塞阪
Come on,Sebastian.
清理
Clear.
有心律
We have sinus rhythm.
那不是TB
That is not TB.
引人注目的电视节目
Compelling television.
做任何你想做的测试
Do whatever tests you want.
我想拿你得TB了治疗
I want to treat you for TB
卡梅伦医生在你脑脊髓液里
Dr. Cameron found low sugar
发现了低糖
in your cerebrospinal fluid.
是TB的经典发现
It's a classic finding of TB.
现在你觉得TB是问题了？
Now you think TB's the problem?
不是
Nah.
TB导致热天的心跳骤停,
TB caused cardiac arrest on a hot day,
你在非洲工作
your work in Africa would be
按说早该比这会儿的问题要多
even more futile than it already is.
你能说重点吗?
Can you get to your point,please?
我办公室的那块白板
That whiteboard in my office.
现在写满症状
We're up to about a dozen symptoms now.
心博停止
Cardiac arrest.
明显不是TB
Clearly not TB.
脑脊髓液糖明显不是 TB
CSF sugar clearly is TB.
其他的可以兼顾
The rest of them could go either way.
除非我们知道需要兼顾什么
Unless we know which ones are which,
我无法诊断你
I can't diagnose you.
我愿意做任何你需要做的试验
I'll take any other tests or treatments ,you might want to prescribe
也就是说你不特殊，但TB特殊
So you're not special. But TB is.
人们死于TB因为我们放任他们死去
People die of TB because we let 'em.
是我们的选择
It's our choice.
人们死于疟疾，因为我们放任
People die of malaria because we let them.
他们死于痢疾，他们……
They die of dysentery,they--
不，TB是我的病
No, TB's my disease.
你拥有一个病?
You own a disease?
很抱歉，我错数了登革热高烧
Well,I'm sorry,I missed the IPO on Dengue Fever.
你看，我知道我自成一派
Look,I know I have a way about me.
我知道我让很多人不爽
I know I piss a lot of people off
并使更多人很苦恼
And a whole lot more I just annoy.
但你是第一个给我遇上的……
But you're the first person that I've ever met
被我干的事困扰的人
who I think is actually annoyed by what I do.
你觉得我没有救人命吗？
Do you think I'm not saving any lives or--
或者那样做不好?
Or is that a bad thing?
现在，我只是要救你的命
Right now,I'm just trying to save your life.
或者是你对抱希望有问题?
Or do you just have a problem with hope?
你知道，我们工作的差别……
You know,the difference between our jobs--
不在于数字和风格……
It's not numbers,or styles
在于我知道我会失败
It's that I know I'm gonna fail.
就算我救了百万人,还会再有百万人染病
Even if I save a million people,,there's gonna be another million
你是对付不了那个
You couldn't handle that.
我觉得你怨恨任何能对付这状况的人
I think you resent anyone who can.
我们是否可以就,你难以置信的讨厌达成一致?
Can't we just agree that you're ,incredibly annoying?
吃药吧
Take the pills.
要不我任由你死，做解剖,然后召开我自己的记者会
Or I let you die,do an autopsy,,call my own press conference
确保让全世界知道你不是死于TB
And make sure the world knows ,that you didn't die of TB.
赞助商会很失望的
Corporate sponsors will be disappointed.
但他们会发现其他疾病
But they'll find another disease.
你干嘛那样做?
Why would you do that?
因为我是个刻薄鬼
Because I'm just a mean son of a bitch.
那么我们仍需解释P-R可变性
So we still have to explain P-R variability,
昏厥、头疼
syncope,headaches--
还有……低糖
And...low sugar?
典型的TB
That was classic TB.
显然不是
Apparently not.
-又做过试验了吗? ,-是
-You rerun the test? ,-Yeah.
好
This is good.
好？简直是诡异
Good? This is bizarre.
诡异好啊
Bizarre is good.
平庸有千种解释
Common has hundreds of explanations.
诡异却几乎没有解释
Bizarre has hardly any.
还有什么可以导致脑脊髓液低糖？
What else could cause low CSF sugar?
嗯，问题该由我来问
Uh-uh. I get to ask the questions.
我觉得你问问题时
I've found you look a lot smarter
比傻瓜般不回答看上去聪明多了
asking questions than dumbly not answering.
血液中胰岛素含量高
High insulin levels in his blood
该很高
They'd have to be very high.
好
Okay
血液胰岛素含量高
Very high insulin levels in his blood
他怎么会胰岛素含量高呢?
How could he get high insulin levels?
我们查了普通血糖，正常
We've checked daily blood sugars,all normal.
看她多聪明，因为她问问题
See how smart she looks? ,Cause she asked the question.
不是葡萄糖菌，因为他没有皮疹
And it's not Glucagonoma because he has no rash.
不是自行导致的，因为他不是傻瓜
It's not self-induced because he's not an idiot
更不是瘤，因为CT和核磁共振都是阴性
And it's not a tumor because the CT ,and the MRI were both negative
只剩下瘤了
Which just leaves tumor.
你干嘛这样做?干嘛忽视我说的话？
Why do you do this? Why do you ignore what I say?
我甚至……小瘤子
Like I'm not even-- Small tumor.
很小，很小
Really,really tiny.
太小了，看不见
So small we can't see it.
胰岛素腺体瘤
Nesidioblastoma.
由胰岛素细胞组成的蜂窝状瘤
An abnormal growth of the insulin-secreting ,cells in his pamcreas
间歇分泌胰岛素
That only intermittently secretes insulin
从而导致压力
In response to stress
就象……我不知道
Like if... Oh,I don't know.
就象有人把一个机器公牛放在11
If someone accidentally puts the ,mechanicals bull on eleven
用手术可以轻易解除
Easily removed by surgery
但是……
Except--
如果小到我们无法看到
If it's so small we can't see it,
又怎么证明它在那呢?
how are we even gonna prove it's there?
她有自作聪明地问了
She asked,looking clever
在他的胰腺上慢跑
Just start hacking away at his pancreas
直到他好转?
until he gets better?
你看不见又怎么证明有呢?
How do you prove something exists ,when you can't see it?
上帝存在吗?
Does God exist?
风在吹吗?
Does the wind blow?
我们知道因为树叶摇动
We know because the leaves move.
看实际
Look for effects.
我们看别的地方吧
Oh,we should look the other way
是卡迪跟你的病人
There's Cuddy with your patient.
豪斯医生
Dr. House
豪斯医生有急诊
Dr. House has an emergency.
我们无法避免她发烧
We can't avoid her forever.
最终她会死
Eventually,she'll die.
你肯定她没得肺癌吗?
You sure she doesn't have breast cancer?
我们觉得你有个瘤,很容易移除
We think you have a tumor.,Easily removed surgically
我们要用个小棍戳它
We're gonna poke it with a stick
如果不是瘤呢?
And if there's no tumor?
什么也不会发生
Nothing happens.
脾动脉，腹腔的左下侧
Splenic artery,it's a hard left off the celiac
如果有瘤呢?
If there is a tumor?
跟你戳的时候一样
What usually happens when you ,poke something with a stick
戳还回去就是了
Pokes back.
他已经戳到了肠系膜
He's stuck in the superior mesenteric.
我就知道该停下来找方向
I knew we should've stopped for directions.
男人啊
Men.
到了
I'm there.
我们要把钙注射进胰腺
We're gonna inject calcium into your pancreas.
蜂窝组织会分泌胰岛素
Beta cells will release insulin
如果有瘤会导致蜂窝组织过量
If there are too many beta cells ,because of a tumor,
你的血糖会超常降低
your blood sugar will drop precipitously.
我们怎么能知道会不会太低呢?
How do we know it won't go too low?
把手指和脚趾都交叉起来吧
Fingers and toes crossed.
开始
Go ahead
葡萄糖维持75
Glucose is holding steady at 75
树叶没有发出声音
No leaves rustling.
再吹
Blow harder
我已经给一个计量了
I already gave him one amp.
那么我看现在是给另一个计量的时候了
Well,I guess now will be the time to ,give him more than one amp
开始降了
It's starting to drop
我的手臂抖了
I think my arm's shaking.
我要给他输葡萄糖
I'm gonna start him on a glucose drip.
他快不行了
He's gonna seize.
不能
Not yet.
继续降
It's continuing to drop
不够快
Not fast enough
他不行了
He's seizing
我们得扭转了
We've gotta reverse this.
40了
He's at 40
推一个计量的D-50,你想要这家伙命吗?
Push an amp of D-50. You wanna kill the guy?
我们回到40了
We're back at 40
恭喜
Congratulations
你有瘤
You have a tumor.
你要跟他外出吗?
Are you gonna go out with him?
那于你何干?
Is that any of your business?
没有
No.
我不觉得会
I don't think so.
两天前，你还握他手呢
Two days ago,you were holding his hand.
怎么变了?
What's changed?
他基本上在非洲，没有未来
He practically lives in Africa.There's no future
换个说法，现在又有太多可能了
On the other hand,maybe there's ,too much of a future now.
你对他没有吸引力
You weren't attracted to him
因为他已经准备为理想献身了
because he was prepared to die for a cause.
你对他有吸引力
You were attracted to him
因为他已经有所作为
because he was actually doing it.
对，就那么简单
Right. It's that simple.
那简单吗?
That was simple?
我给他贴了个标签，然后出发了
I put a label on him and go from there.
嗯，每个人都那么干
Mm,everybody does it.
我们是我们想像那样的人
We are who people think we are.
人们觉得他是伟大的医生所以给他东西
People think he's a great doctor ,so they give him stuff.
他是个伟大的医生
He is a great doctor.
跟事实无关
The reality is irrelevant.
我来证明
I'll prove it.
认识我的人觉得我是坏蛋
People who know me see me as an ass.
象对待坏蛋那样对我
Treat me as an ass.
不认识我的人看见一个跛子
People who don't know me see a cripple
象对跛子那样对我
Treat me like a cripple.
哪有不占这种便宜的自私的混蛋啊?
What sort of selfish jerk wouldn't ,take advantage of that fact?
哇
Ow!
哦，我的天啊
Oh,my goodness.
你没事吗?
Are you okay?
对
Yeah.
我真抱歉
I am so sorry
完全是我的错
It was completely my fault.
没事，我没事
It's nothing. I'm fine.
那……我就放心了
Well,I--I'm very relieved.
-我感觉糟透了,-请别介怀
-I feel terrible,-Please don't worry about it
-我没事,-你肯定?
-I'm fine. ,-You sure?
-嗯,-好
-Mm-hmm. ,-Okay.
一切都好吗?
How's everything?
我得走了，我的脚疼死了
I'm gonna go. My foot's killing me.
-你干嘛来着？,-哦，没事
-Oh,what did you do,-Oh,it was nothing.
都是我的错
It was all my fault.
哦，听着，小包，我没事的，好吗?
Yeah,listen. Bogale,relax,okay?
我周二回去
I'm,uh--I'm gonna be back on Tuesday.
告诉萨力我会给她带个新支架回去
Tell Sarni I'm gonna bring her a new brace.
好的
All right.
以防万一
Just in case.
你拿到了吗?
You get 'em?
六个月的用量
Six-month supply.
该够你的了
Should fix you right up.
你来补充的时候再见了
I'll see you when you come back for a refill?
对，两个月见
Yeah,I'll see you in two months.
你会把它们送人吗?
You gonna give 'em away?
你知道会发生什么
Well,you know how these things happen.
你把包存在飞机上
You leave a bag on the airplane.
或者是药片掉水沟里了
Drop some pills down the drain.
我有个主意
I have an idea.
你可以带补充到非洲来
You could,uh,bring me the refill in Africa.
我看不行
I don't think so.
你真的喜欢给豪斯工作吗?
You actually like working for House?
你觉得这让人满足吗?
You find this satisfying?
嗯
Well.
-看到你真好,-多谢
-It's good to see you,-Thank you
多谢，我很感激
Thank you. I appreciate that.
多谢支持...
I appreciate the support...
并不因为每8秒钟死个孩子
It's not about the kids dying every eight seconds.
是因为媒体猛击,
It's about the media stroking,
阿谀奉承
the adulation,the pats on the head
那是你跟他之间的问题，是吗?
That's your problem with him,isn't it?
嗯，他喜欢你看，他统统接受了
Well,look at him. He loves it. Eats it up.
对，那家伙以他的所为为乐呢
Yeah,the man actually enjoys what he does
听着，是我救了他的命
Listen,I saved his life.
也就是说我得到了,由他挽救的所有生命的信任
That means I get credit for every life ,he saves from here on out
我保证让斯德哥尔摩知道
I'll make sure Stockholm knows.